《德古拉》前情回顾…
Previously on Dracula...
很荣幸能为你们举办订婚宴
It'll be my honor to host your engagement party.
一切都不同了
Things will never be the same.
你要结婚了  这才是问题所在
You are to be married, and that is that.
她就是Ilona
She is Ilona.
不许你再提起Mina Murray
You must never again
和我妻子长得像这事儿
mention Mina Murray's resemblance to my wife.
我需要你的血去创造血清
I need your blood to create a serum
这样你才能去征服阳光
so you are able to conquer daylight.
我想你去查出
I want you to find out
关于Shaw将军的一切
everything about this General Shaw.
他是一个强大的对手
He's a powerful ally of my competitors.
你想知道的
Vera Markham can tell you
关于Shaw将军
all you need to know
Vera Markham会告诉你
about Shaw.
你是？
Yes?
你想雇佣我
You wish to employ my services
让Renfield先生来解答一个问题
in order to get Mr. Renfield to answer one question.
啊！
Unh!
Grayson先生  你在这儿干嘛？
Mr. Grayson. What are you doing here?
我知道我不应该在这儿
I know I shouldn't be here,
但没时间了
but there's no time.
没时间干嘛？
Time for what?
不  你必须离开  立刻  要不…
No. You must leave, immediately, or...
我会走的
I'll go.
我保证
I promise.
但我必须告诉你
But I must tell you,
你在犯一个错误
you're making a mistake.
严重的错误
A terrible mistake.
- 你什么意思？  - Harker
- What do you mean? - Harker.
你知道的  他绝不会带给你快乐
He'll never be able to make you happy, and you know it.
你怎样这样说
How dare you.
没时间自欺欺人了  Mina
Now is not the time for lies, Mina.
你知道这是真的
You know it's the truth.
如果不是  就说出来
If it isn't, say it.
看着我的眼睛  告诉我
Look me in the eyes and say it,
- 那我就走  - 不 不 不
- and I'll go. - No, no, no.
我…我爱…我爱Jonathan  不是别人
I-I love... I love Jonathan, and no other,
他会成为我的丈夫
and he will be my husband.
整天都赖在床上
Of all the days to lie-in.
你不知道今晚前
Don't you know we have a million things
我们还有一箩筐事情要做吗？
to do before tonight?
- 它仍继续？  - 当然仍在继续
- It's still on? - Of course it's still on!
除非你重新考虑
Unless you've reconsidered.
不不不  当然不是
No. No. No, of course not.
那么  看在上帝的面子上
Well then, for goodness' sake,
起来吧  亲爱的
get up, darling.
这么重要的日子
You mustn't waste another second
别浪费一分一秒啊
of this momentous day.
你的婚宴在伦敦可是前无古人
Yours is going to be the most spectacular
盛世非凡呢
engagement party London has ever seen.
小心点儿  这很脆弱
Be careful. That's very fragile.
来看看你的第一测试项目
Come and meet your first test subject.
拜托用线把它和门连上
Place it in line with the door, please.
没有什么东西不能有阴影！
And no obstruction that may cast a shadow!
我不会靠得太近的  教授
I wouldn't get too close, Professor.
就算你不认同
I think you'll find her suitable,
我觉得她挺合适
if not exactly agreeable.
这儿还有很多技术挑战
There are many technical challenges,
但我相信在给定时间内  我们会战胜它的
but I believe we will surmount them, given time.
时间是奢侈的  我们没时间
Time is a luxury we do not have.
我必须马上在阳光下行走
I must walk in sunlight soon.
人们起疑了
People are getting suspicious.
你不明白吗？
Do you understand?
对了  Renfield去哪了？
By the way, where's Renfield?
他本应该在实验室
He was meant to accompany the lab equipment.
到处都找不到Renfield
Renfield was nowhere to be found.
所以我才自己动手
I had to do it myself.
Renfield先生
Mr. Renfield.
来一个小旅程吧  就你和我
We are about to embark on a journey, you and I.
以一个问题为开端
It begins with a single question,
以你的回答为终点
and it ends with your answer to that question.
为了让你记住这点
I want you to remember that,
我再说一遍
so I will say it again.
以你的回答  为终点
It ends with your answer.
所以你懂的  无论你觉得
So you see, no matter how helpless
多么无助  多么漫长
you may feel, no matter how lengthy,
多么低贱  多么不悦
debasing, and disagreeable
这个“旅程”
the journey may prove,
最终  都是由你掌控
ultimately, you are in control.
能开始了吗？
Let's get started, shall we?
在我的专业内  我深感自豪
Though I take great pride in my profession,
虽然后来变得…
it has become...
繁琐复杂
tedious of late.
可是  毕竟
There are, after all,
唯一不变的就是
only so many variations
我可以变着花样的玩儿
on a theme one can play.
放了我
Release me.
啊！
Unh!
当然  每一种用具都是独一无二的
Each client is unique, of course.
方法各有迥异
The methods vary,
但是结果必然相同
but the result is inevitably the same.
我警告你
I'm warning you,
后果很严重
there will be repercussions.
我常常想
I often think,
“也许这一次  Janina”
"Perhaps this time, Janina.
“就一次  仅此一次
"This time, for once,
“简单的回答了
"The client will dispense with
我的第一问
all the bluster and defiance
所有的咆哮和反抗
and simply answer the question
都将被免除”
the first time I ask it."
Alexander Grayson爱着谁？
Who does Alexander Grayson love?
哦  好吧
Oh, well.
也许得下次
Perhaps next time.
―――真 爱 字 幕 组 ―――
出  品
翻译：幸福ing形式  资本论and圣经
翻译：依依yiyi  飞越无限
翻译：heart青春时光
组长：火星人善良凡凡
后期：飞越无限
校对  监制：幸福ing形式
招贤纳士QQ群：233183580
―― 祝观影愉快 ――
――― 德 古 拉 ―――
第一季 第五集
这是Shaw将军的个人账户
These are General Shaw's personal accounts.
都在这儿了  所属Bellamy公司
It's all there, under Bellamy Limited.
Bellamy公司？
Bellamy?
帝国军火  唯一股东
Sole shareholder, empire munitions.
帝国军火？
Empire munitions?
Show从军火制造商那里收钱？
Shaw's receiving money from an arms manufacturer?
七月份  六万磅
60,000 pounds in July.
七月  就在那时…帝国中标了
July, that's when... That's when the empire
八个新战舰
won the tender for eight new warships.
他拿了佣金
He got commission.
Shaw将军这是受贿罪
General Shaw is taking bribes.
Harker  请问
Harker, please.
你打算如何处置这些信息？
What do you plan to do with this information?
我知道你拜托我操办这个派对
I know you begged me to organize this party
我也确实答应你了 但并不意味着
and I agreed, but that doesn't give you
你就可以当甩手姑奶奶了
the right to be an idle princess.
你有宾客名单 我有回执
You have the guest list. I have the replies.
你负责把这两个对照一下
You check the former against the latter,
因为饭店明天中午前就要最终名单了
and the kitchen needs the final count by noon.
宾客名单绝对出错了
This list, it's all wrong.
Davenport 爵士 Rothcoft爵士？
Lord Davenport. Lord Rothcroft?
是难以想到
Who'd ever have guessed
Jonathan还有这样大牌的朋友呢？
that Jonathan had such distinguished friends?
是啊 可他们并不是他的朋友
Yes, but they're not his friends.
至少 他从来没向我提及过他们
At least, he's never mentioned them.
恐怕这都是我的错
All my doing, I'm afraid.
是我坚持让他邀请那些巨头的
I insisted he invite them.
Grasyson 先生的盛情小女子有些承受不起
It's all rather overwhelming, Mr. Grayson.
您不觉得您过于大包大揽了吗？
Are you sure it's not too much of an imposition?
绝非如此
Not at all.
都是Westenra小姐“法力无边”才让这
This is just an empty stage upon which Miss Westenra
才让这平凡的舞台变得妙不可言
has lavished her formidable magic.
总算有人欣赏我的苦劳了
At least somebody appreciates all my hard work.
Alexander! 你一定不会相信…
Alexander! You won't believe what...
Mina.
介意和我借一步说话吗？
Could we have a word privately, please?
女士们  请原谅我们的失陪
Ladies, if you will excuse us.
Shaw绝对不是吃素的
Shaw is far from a saint, and I've got
我已经找到了证明这个的依据
the evidence to prove it.
现在不要管他
Not now.
- 我已经开了个会  - 听我的 别插手
- I've just had a meeting. - I said, leave it.
Lucy 将来你可能会觉得
Lucy, you'll probably think me
我是个被宠坏的孩子
a spoiled child...
不可能
Impossible.
发生什么问题了吗？
What's wrong?
我做了个这辈子最令人为难的梦
I had the most perplexing dream.
真的？
Really?
那种梦  是吧？
That kind of dream?
不  才不是那种梦呢
No. Not that kind of dream.
告诉我…
Tell me...
梦里的Jonathan是比现在更谨慎呢
Was the dream version of Jonathan more circumspect,
还是有更宽厚的肩膀呢？
or was it merely a matter of circumference?
不是
No.
甚至都没…
And it wasn't even...
这个梦无关Jonathan
It wasn't even Jonathan.
当然不是 我自然梦到的是Jonathan
Yes, of course. Of course it was Jonathan.
Renfield  昨晚去Victoria 站点
Renfield went to Victoria Station last night
要取一些实验工具
to pick up some laboratory equipment.
他没来
He never arrived,
从昨晚他就蒸发了
and he has not been heard from since.
他可能只是路上耽搁了
Well, perhaps he was detained.
他都失踪九个小时了
He's been missing nine hours.
要是耽搁了他会告诉我们
He would have sent word.
我要去联系警察吗？
Shall I contact the police?
不 不 警方不能介入
No, no. No police.
这次绝对要做的完全不留痕迹
This must be handled with the utmost discretion.
在公司的这个节骨眼上
At this point of our business,
Grayson 能源承受不了任何丑闻
Grayson Energy cannot afford a scandal.
我确信您比任何人都了解这一点
I'm sure you understand that more than anyone.
自然如此
Of course.
那好  我从医院太平间开始排查
Well, I'll start with the hospitals, the morgues.
他取设备前
Did he have any appointments prior
有提前说过要干啥了吗？
to picking up the equipment?
就说去当地钢铁公司
Only to gather some information
收集些情报
from local steel mills.
好的  这样就略微缩小了范围
Well, that narrows things down a bit.
他可不是不显眼的人
He's hardly inconspicuous.
让我一个人调查吧
Leave it with me.
Jonathan?
Mina 我现在必须失陪下
I really must be going, Mina.
等等…名单真是对的？
Wa... Is this list right?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我有些紧急公务不得不去
I-I have some urgent business to attend to.
我们稍后再讨论这个
We'll have to discuss this later.
可是今晚就是订婚夜了啊
But the party is tonight.
就剩几个小时了
It's in a few hours.
好吧  我是加了几个人  就这样
Well, I-I made a few additions, is all.
工作上的泛泛之交  以及诸如此类
Business acquaintances and so forth.
我担心的不是加了几个人
It's not the additions that concern me,
而是你漏了的
it's the people you have disinvited.
像是谁？
Like who?
所有你在报社的朋友  比如Szabo
All your friends at the paper. Szabo.
Szabo?
Mina想象下  我们可是提供酒水的
Think, Mina. We're serving alcohol.
你真的希望他来拿香槟杯子玩杂耍
Do you really want him juggling champagne bottles
例行公事的跳小熊舞？
and doing his dancing bear routine?
我确信他一定不会失态
I'm sure he will behave himself.
不行！
The answer is no!
我们正在走向整个世界
We're moving up in the world,
在这途中失去几个朋友
and its only natural that we're gonna lose
再自然不过了
a few friends on the way.
这是你内心真实的声音？
Would you listen to yourself?
那么 还有谁要来？
So, who else will be in attendance?
Rothcroft  还有其他几个人
Rothcroft. A few others.
我真切的希望
I do hope there won't be another
今晚不要出啥大乱子
grand spectacle this evening.
最好还是孤立
Brash Americans like Grayson
像Grayson这种傲气的美国人
are best left twisting in the wind.
一旦他们发现钱不能收买一切
Once they realize their money can't buy cooperation,
除非被惹恼了  他们自己就会打包走人
they pack up and move on... unless provoked.
这是自然  先生
Of course, sir.
不
No.
只要没有您的吩咐
There should never be any direct action against
就不会直接对他用强
Grayson without your express permission.
我以为你会和Lucy一起呆在Carfax
I thought you'd be at Carfax with Lucy.
我本来是
I was,
但是我觉得我最好回家休息下
but I thought I'd come home and rest a while.
你母亲一定会为你骄傲的
Your mother would be so proud of you.
嗯
Hmm.
你把Jonathan发掘成了一个好男人
You've found a fine man in Jonathan.
她一定会对你的选择高兴的
I know she'd be happy with your choice.
可能她会更喜欢一个月前的
A month ago, perhaps,
那个从前的Jonathan
with the old Jonathan.
但他变了
But he's changed.
怎么变的？
In what way?
好吧  就从这开始吧
Well, to start with,
他结交了一帮新朋友…
he's got an entirely new set of friends...
其中多数是商业伙伴…
business associates, most of them...
而且他们是有爵位的富人
and they're titled and wealthy
年纪比他大很多
and much older than he is.
这很平常啊
That's perfectly natural.
他转行了
He's in a new line,
必然要结交新朋友
he's bound to make new acquaintances.
这倒是  但他和多数老朋友断绝往来
Yes, but he's cut ties with most, if not all,
似乎他们的存在可有可无
of his old friends, as though they're expendable.
我不禁想…
And I can't help but think...
你也会变得可有可无?
That you might become expendable as well?
我必须承认  Renfield先生…
I must admit, Mr. Renfield...
您的耐力令人印象深刻
Your stoicism is impressive,
但绝对算不上惊人
but by no means a surprise.
- Rodrigo?  - 不
- Rodrigo? - No.
不要
Please.
你真坚强…
Oh, you are strong...
看来你很能吃苦
And clearly no stranger to suffering.
无论在怎样的环境下
Admirable traits
这都是令人钦佩的特质
under virtually every other circumstance.
噢  Renfield先生
Alas, Mr. Renfield,
别这样  至少此时此地别这样
not here, not now.
这里就你我两人
There is just me and you.
你只需要…回答问题!
The question...and the answer!
Alexander Grayson爱谁?
Who does Alexander Grayson love?
Renfield被绑了
Renfield's been abducted.
谁干的?
By whom?
我们只能假设是恶龙会
We can only assume it's the Order.
但日落后
But until the sun goes down,
我才能救他
I'm powerless to help him.
你认为他们会撬开他的嘴?
Do you think they can break him?
他出卖我之前就会死
He will die before he says a word against me.
很好  那问题就解决了
Very well, then. Problem solved.
今天不能让任何事
We cannot let anything
分散我们对实验的注意力
distract us from today's test.
总共需要多长时间?
How long will this entire process take?
我会用共鸣器
I will use the resonator to generate voltage
给一对电桨生成电压
to a pair of electrical paddles,
然后放入胸腔
then apply them to the subject's chest
尝试让其产生心跳
and attempt to jolt the heart into beating.
之后我会给她大剂量注射
Then I will give the subject a massive injection of the serum.
如果成功
If it works,
你尽快将技术运用在我身上
you will immediately repeat the whole process on me.
但我没有足够的血清
But I won't have an adequate supply of the serum.
所以过程会比较缓慢
As you can see, it's a slow process.
我没有装备!
I don't have the equipment!
等等
Hold a second.
- 打扰一下  - 怎么了  先生?
- Excuse me. - Yes, sir?
我找Havershim先生
I'm looking for a Mr. Havershim.
如果是生意
If it's business,
联系圣路易斯办公室
call my St. Louis office.
我电联过圣路易斯办公室
I have called your St. Louis office,
堪萨斯城办公室
and your Kansas City office,
以及卡森城办公室
and your Carson City office.
先别说  让我猜猜
Don't tell me, let me guess.
你是Alexander Grayson
You're Alexander Grayson.
没错
That's correct.
你想买我的斯威特沃特项目
And you want to buy my Sweetwater operation.
还有双驾横木矿产
And your Doubletree mine.
我出价
I am willing to offer you
两万美元
20,000 of your American dollars.
当真?
Really?
真令人印象深刻
Impressive.
Grayson先生  你要么是个勇敢的人
Mr. Grayson, you are either a very brave man
要么就是个蠢蛋
or a very foolish one.
赤手空拳就敢过来
This is a rough country to be traveling unarmed.
我不喜欢枪
I don't like guns.
这个时候买矿是一个
This is a singularly
非常不凑巧的时间  先生
inopportune moment to purchase a mine, sir.
到底怎么回事?
What the hell?
联邦税率正在上调
Federal taxes on minerals are set to escalate,
如果你坚持要买
so if you insist on making the purchase,
提供一个售后回租条款
make sure you tender an option
可以减少损失
with a leaseback provision to avoid the levies.
先生  来点威士忌怎么样?
Whiskey, sir?
谢谢
Thank you.
你叫?
And what's your name?
Renfield. R.M. Renfield  先生
Renfield. R.M. Renfield, esquire.
Alexander!
你说的没错
You were right.
Renfield昨天下午四点左右
Renfield was abducted outside of Empire and Colonial
在殖民帝国外被捕了
yesterday afternoon around 4:00.
我问了一个新闻小贩
I found a newspaper vendor.
他目睹了整个过程
He witnessed the whole thing.
- 具体描述?  - 三个男人
- Did he give a description? - Mm, three men.
一个打他
One hit him, the others
另外两个抓住他扔进了马车
grabbed him and threw him into a carriage.
他通知警方了吗?
Did he notify the police?
他以为那就是警察
He assumed it was the police.
我发现了这个
I found this.
哪儿来的?
Where?
大门外的水沟槽
In the gutter just outside the main entrance.
通知警方吗?
Shall I notify the police?
不
No.
有这个就够了
This is all I need.
我以为
I was beginning to think
我得独自开始了
I would be forced to start without you.
我有紧急事务要处理
I had an urgent matter to attend to.
还有比这更紧急的吗?
And what could be more urgent than this?
我终于有了Renfield的线索
I finally have a lead on Renfield.
可以开始了吗?
Shall we proceed?
首先从心脏开始
First, we start its heart.
1,000伏  一圈
1,000 volts, circuit one.
3,000伏!
3,000 volts!
3,000伏  一圈
3,000 volts, circuit one.
有心跳了
It's beating.
成功了
Success.
你现在不能走!
You can't leave now!
我必须去找Renfield
I must find Renfield.
你要举行一个派对
You are about to host a party
恶龙会的人都要出席
at which known members of the Order will be present.
教授  如果你不想失去手臂
Professor, if you ever valued that arm,
就放开我
take it off mine...
马上!
immediately!
你好
Hello.
多谢前来
Thank you.
- 马上回来  亲爱的  - 好的
- Back in a tick, darling. - Okay.
见到你很高兴
Lovely to see you.
我向他保证我不会跳得和熊一样
I promised him I will not do my dancing bear.
我想我应该去照看一下女士们了
I think it's time for me to see to the women.
如果你原谅我的失礼的话
If you will excuse me.
- Jonathan  -Murray医生
- Jonathan. - Dr. Murray.
Mina  你看上去真漂亮
Mina, you look lovely.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是对的
You were right.
我开始忘记我是谁了
I was beginning to forget who I am.
我不会忘
I never will.
我一直在你身边提醒你
And I will always be here to remind you.
你保证？
Promise?
我希望Grayson先生
I hope Mr. Grayson likes
喜欢我们的的布置
what we've done with the place.
哦  他还没到么？
Well, he... He hasn't arrived?
恩  没  还没呢  他仍在途中
Mm-mm, no, not yet. He's still to arrive.
Grayson先生爱谁呢？
Who does Mr. Grayson love?
Renfield先生 他爱谁呢？
Mr. Renfield, who does he love?
Alexander Grayson先生爱谁呢？
Who does Mr. Alexander Grayson love?
我愿意提供给你
I am willing to offer you 20,000
20000美元
of your American dollars.
Grayson先生
Mr. Grayson,
你要么是个勇敢的人
you are either a very brave man...
要么就是个蠢蛋
or a very foolish one.
赤手空拳
This is a rough country
就敢过来
to be traveling unarmed.
这个时候买矿是一个
This is a singularly inopportune moment
非常不凑巧的时间  先生
to purchase a mine, sir.
到底怎么回事?
What the hell?
联邦税率正在上调
Federal taxes are set to escalate,
如果你坚持要买
so if you insist on making the purchase,
提供一个售后回租条款
make sure you tender an option
可以减少损失
with a leaseback provision to avoid the levies.
先生  来点威士忌怎么样?
Whiskey, sir?
谢谢
Thank you.
他们想杀了你
They mean to kill you.
啊!
Unh!
你说的够多了
That's enough outta you.
你感觉自己很聪明么？  恩？
You think you're so smart? Huh?
来吧  伙计  一起吧
Come on, boys! Join in.
恩!
Unh!
啊!
Aah!
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
Renfield先生
Mr. Renfield?
Mr. Renfield.
Grayson爱谁呢？
Who does Grayson love?
奇怪了 没有指挥者的踪影呢
Curious. No sign of the ringmaster.
毫无疑问的是精心设计了他的大厅入口
No doubt choreographing his grand entrance.
实际上我说的是他的手下
I actually meant his man.
你知道的  那个大个头的家伙
You know, the very large one
总做些夸张演讲的的家伙
who makes all the turgid announcements.
他叫什么来着？
What's his name?
提到大厅入口
Speaking of grand entrances.
她在找Grayson
She's looking for Grayson.
你怎么知道的
How can you tell?
因为只有他不在
Because he's the only one who isn't here.
可怜的人啊
Poor thing.
把她最好的青春
Spent her best years
花在了她喜欢的男人身上
having any man she pleases,
但是现在呢？
but now?
Wetherby小姐碰到了一个并不愉快的前景
Lady Wetherby faces the unpleasant prospect
没有一个人是她内心想要的
of not having the one man she really wants
而他的丈夫又枯萎在病床上
while her husband withers away in his sickbed.
我为我的迟到表示歉意
I apologize for being late.
我希望一切都如您所想  Murray小姐
I hope everything is as you wish, Miss Murray.
非常感谢  为所有事
Thank you so much, for everything.
恩
你看上去很漂亮
You look very lovely.
请原谅我的失礼
You'll have to excuse me, hmm?
- 顺便谢谢你  - 为什么？
- Thank you, incidentally. - What for?
在你的帮助下
With your help,
我们找到了Renfield的所在
we managed to locate Renfield.
一言以蔽之  一切安好
Suffice it to say, all is good,
尽管我还不知道谁应对此负责
though I'm no closer to knowing who's responsible.
- 他？  - 他没事  我向你保证
- Is he... - He's quite all right. I assure you.
现在  关于Shaw将军
Now, what's this interesting
你有什么有趣的消息么？
news you have regarding General Shaw?
- 相当棒的宴会  - 恩
- Quite the party. - Mm.
他肯定是个很值钱的雇员
He must be a very valuable employee.
你感觉Harker怎么样？
What do you think of Harker?
我认为他会很有用
I think he could be useful.
如果一定要说点什么的话
And if anything,
就是他有野心
he's ambitious.
当然你没考虑招募新人
Surely you're not thinking of recruitment.
恩  他还不够老练
Well, he's a little rough around the edges,
但我们总得用点新鲜血液
but we could always use some fresh blood.
不列颠为对抗奥斯曼的战争武装得越多
The more Britain arms itself for war against the Ottomans,
Shaw将军以权谋私的就越多
the more General Shaw stands to gain.
实际上这个国家做的每一笔交易
On virtually every munitions deal this country makes,
他都从中分成
he's getting a cut.
合同总价值的10%
10% of the total value of the contracts.
Harker  这些指控
Harker, these allegations...
不只这些指控
More than allegations.
我查了他的账户  他们很是小心
I've checked his accounts. They're meticulous.
听着  Harker
Look, Harker,
我的意图是使他陷入窘境
my intention was to embarrass the man,
而不是查他老底起诉他
not have him dragged up on charges.
但Shaw是个伪君子
But Shaw's a hypocrite.
身居高位的卖国贼
A traitor of the highest order.
你也没暗示我放手此事  对吗？
You're not suggesting I just let this go, are you?
啊
Ah.
Grayson先生  还有新郎
Mr. Grayson, and the groom.
Jayne Wetherby女士
Lady Jayne Wetherby.
我邀请的她  希望你别介意
I invited her. I hope you don't mind.
当然不
Of course not.
恩  失陪一下
Um, if you'll excuse me.
Harker.
我想你了
I've missed you.
你看起来如此的秀色可餐
You look absolutely ravishing.
哦  那最好是赶紧就餐
Oh, far better to be ravished.
你刚才自己去哪里了？
Where have you been keeping yourself?
貌似有人掳走
It seems somebody abducted
并折磨了我的人  Renfield
and tortured my man, Renfield.
哦  天啊
Oh, good lord!
为什么会有人做那事?
Why would someone do something like that?
可能是一些过去的商业争斗
Probably some old business rival.
别担心
And don't worry.
事情都已经解决了
It's all been resolved.
- 可以吗  - 好
- Shall we?  - Yes.
Grayson先生?
Uh, Mr. Grayson?
请许我把你介绍给我老板
Please let me introduce you to my employer.
Grayson先生  哦  Wetherby女士
Uh, Mr. Grayson, um, Lady Wetherby,
这是Browning先生
this is Mr. Browning.
- Browning先生  - Grayson先生
- Mr. Browning. - Mr. Grayson.
- Davenport大人  - 我们见过
- Lord Davenport. - We've met.
Rothcroft大人
Lord Rothcroft.
- Rothcroft大人  - Grayson先生
- Lord Rothcroft. - Mr. Grayson.
- 还有Godalming大人  - Godalming大人              -
- And Lord Godalming. - Lord Godalming.
欢迎来我家
Welcome to my home.
很高兴你能邀请我们
Very kind of you to have us.
先生们  请原谅我们
Uh, gentlemen, please excuse us.
我等不及去认识你了
I cannot wait to get you to myself.
所以你会的
Hmm, and so you shall.
Grayson先生
Mr. Grayson.
打扰一下  Grayson先生?
Excuse me, Mr. Grayson?
我想让你见见我的导师和朋友
I would like you to meet my mentor and my friend,
Van Helsing教授
Professor Van Helsing.
见到你真高兴
It's a pleasure to meet you,
Van Helsing教授
Professor Van Helsing.
很荣幸见到你
Honored to meet you.
教授可是其领域的先驱啊
The Professor is a pioneer in his field.
真的吗
Is that so?
Grayson的人  Renfield被绑架了
Grayson's man, Mr. Renfield, was abducted.
- 真的?  - 是真的
- Really? - Mm.
被绑走和虐待?
Abducted and tortured.
是组织干的吗？
Was that Order business?
当然不是
Absolutely not.
Grayson先生一直都很热心
Mr. Grayson's been kind enough to give us
为我们今晚的庆祝提供他的房子
his home for our celebration tonight.
他确实非常慷慨
How remarkably generous of him.
谢谢你  教授  乐意效劳
Thank you, Professor. A pleasure.
Murray小姐
Miss Murray.
怎么了教授?
Professor?
一切还好吗?
Is everything all right?
失陪一下
Excuse me.
好了  先生们女士们
All right, ladies and gentlemen.
为了我漂亮
For my beautiful daughter,
又让我总是骄傲的女儿Mina
Mina, who has always made me proud,
还有我一直看做是儿子的Jonathan
and for Jonathan, who I have long considered a son.
Mina  我  希望你母亲能在这儿
Mina, I only wish your mother were here
见证你变成的那个女人
to witness the woman that you've become.
请和我一起
Please, join me
为这对儿快乐的夫妻举杯
in raising a glass to the happy couple.
为Mina和Jonathan
To Mina and Jonathan.
为Mina和Jonathan!
To Mina and Jonathan!
女士们先生们
Uh, ladies and gentlemen.
今晚我想…
I'd, um, well,
我想从感谢Murray医师开始
I would like to start by thanking Dr. Murray,
不仅仅是为他亲切的言词
not just for his kind words this evening
还有他终生的善良热心
but for a whole lifetime of kindness,
并允许我娶他的女儿来结束!
culminating in him allowing me to marry his daughter!
我说"允许"  但是
I say "Allowing," But,
恩  任何了解Mina的人
um, anyone who knows Mina
都知道她只走自己认定的道路
knows that she follows her own path,
而那条路…
and that path...
那条指引她去使我这个
that path has led her to make me
最最快乐幸运的人活着的道路
the very happiest and very luckiest man alive.
听  听
Hear, hear.
Grayson先生!
Mr. Grayson!
今晚的欢宴堪称盛景
Tonight's festivities are nothing short of spectacular.
现在我已经苦苦思索良久
Now I've thought long and hard about
如何最好地去表达
how best to express
我对你的感激之情
my gratitude to you,
最后  我决定为你提供对我来说
and in the end, decided that it's right for me
最最珍贵的东西…
to offer you what I consider most precious...
第一曲舞的特权
The privilege of the first dance.
能换我吗？
May I cut in?
抱歉  我得透透气
Excuse me. I need some air.
Grayson有个秘密  我能看得出来
Grayson has a secret. I can tell.
那会是什么？
And what might that be?
我不完全确定
I'm not entirely sure.
他是个没有档案的神秘家伙
He's a man of mystery without biography.
好吧  对于一个美国人来说那是很寻常的
Well, that's hardly unusual for an American.
那些反对他的人经常最后成死鬼了
Those who oppose him frequently end up dead.
那些经常反对你的
Those that oppose you
最后经常也会以死告终
frequently end up dead.
这只是巧合  再无其它
It's coincidence. Nothing more.
说到
Speaking of which,
他来到伦敦
his arrival in London
牵涉到了一些非常不吉利的东西
coincided with something rather more ominous.
哪个？
Which is?
你搜寻的老东西出现了
The advent of the old one you seek.
我给你带来了那老东西的骨灰  在罐子里
I brought you the old one's ashes in a jar.
是吗？
Did you?
Alexander Grayson  一个吸…
Alexander Grayson, a vamp...
荒谬  不可能
Ridiculous. Never.
你不会是第一个
You would not be the first woman
被欲望蒙蔽眼睛的女人
to be blinded by desire.
第一个猎人  是的…
The first huntsman, yes...
但不是第一个女人
but not the first woman.
滚开!
Go away!
我在纽约获悉这儿的很多消息
A lot of information I learned here in New York
我在Charles Remick学法律时
while I was studying law
一个主张废除死刑的人
under Charles Remick, a white abolitionist.
提议我在密苏里酒吧接受考试
He made a motion I be examined under the Missouri bar.
我猜测你通过了
I presume you passed.
我加入了圣路易斯的一家公司
I joined a firm in St. Louis
而且被送到西部
and was sent out west
去处理反索赔的事
to sort out a cross-claim.
委托人反对我的种族
The client took exception to my race.
因为我为自己辩护
I was set upon by ruffians,
我被恶棍袭击  而且被囚禁
and imprisoned for the crime of defending myself.
圣路易斯的公司怎么说?
What about the firm in St. Louis?
他们和我摆脱了关系
Well, they washed their hands of me.
我怀疑他们一直都这样想的
I suspect that was their intent all along.
无亲无友  身无分文
I was left friendless and penniless.
只能说…
Suffice to say...
事情并未按计划进行
things did not go to plan.
对这一切我心存感激  先生
I'm very grateful for this, sir.
希望你别介意我问一句
I hope I don't undermine that
“为什么？”
gratitude by asking, "Why?"
你是一名高水准的律师  Renfield
You're a lawyer of the highest caliber, Renfield.
我需要一名律师
I require a lawyer.
我太了解流浪的滋味儿了
I too know what it's like to live as an outcast,
我外表看起来高端大气
outside what passes for polite society,
其实不然
but rarely is.
绝对超乎你的想象
More than you could possibly imagine.
你是谜一样的男人  Grayson先生
You are a man of secrets, Mr. Grayson.
我只能这样说
That much, I can see.
但为了我的职业操守
But I owe it to my profession and my good name
和职业信誉  我得说
to tell you that I can only work for a man
我只为完全信任的人工作
who trusts me completely.
那我告诉你我所有的秘密
Then you shall know all my secrets,
你的人生将从此改变
and your life will never be the same.
所以这算承诺吗？
Is that a promise?
12年前